There could be an iframe on their page.
There could be an iframe on your page.
You could be ifframing your own page. I
framing your own page to create a null
origin which is a separate origin from
your attacker page and then use that
null origin to open up another page.
[music]
>> Best part of hacking when you can just
you know critical thing.
Yeah, dude.
>> [music]
>> All right, hackers. I was just looking
into this and I think I figured out how
threat locker elevation control works.
Okay, so when a user launches an
elevated process or they try to threat
Locker agent will hook that into its own
elevation flow. So we don't see any UAC
prompt or anything. The threat locker
admin will be able to grant that process
um elevated permissions for a certain
amount of time or whatever. Very
granular control there. And then the
threat locker agent on the user's device
injects a modified process security
token which will elevate that process
directly. This is awesome because it
avoids things like UAC which um leaves
NLM hashes and stuff like that in memory
right in LSAS.exe.
Um it creates a timebounded elevation
right and it does the elevation to the
process rather than to the user. really
great stuff. But of course, there's
always like maintenance mode and that
sort of thing if you have to get in
there and do a bunch of administrative
activities. Great stuff by Threat Locker
once again. All right, let's go back to
the show.
All right, my guy. This is the episode
of Clientside Advanced Topics. I
freaking love this, man. I freaking love
it.
>> This is your uh this is your dream.
>> Yes. Um All right. So, we got a lot of
stuff on the docket today about client
side advanced topics. Essentially the
the vision for this episode was just me
kind of brain dumping all of the things
that I think are a little bit above um
you know intermediate tier uh as far as
client side hacking goes. So I'm going
to kind of lay out all those things that
I think are really cool and you are
going to play the listener and try to
repeat these back to me and try to
ingest this information and make sure
I'm not like going too fast or too over
the top with the explanation.
>> Yeah. Yeah. It's really easy to make
mental leaps whenever you're the, you
know, quote unquote expert on it, right?
So,
>> exactly.
>> Perfect. [snorts]
>> Quote unquote expert on it. What is that
supposed to mean?
>> So, this is actually, this is actually a
really good point. I never know how much
flattery someone can take. Like, I I
think you're a super expert. Whenever I
talk to anybody and someone asks me
like, you know, who do I think the most
talented hacker is? Like, you're almost
always the first name out of my mouth.
And so, but then I never know if people
want to hear that to their face. Like, I
feel like usually you'd be like, nah or
whatever, right? So,
>> anyways, it makes feel awkward. I do
that. You know, if you're if you're if
you're playing it up, then I play it
down. And if you're playing it down,
then what are you talking about? You
know, so there's always some back and
forth, I guess.
>> I like it.
>> Um, appreciate you though, Joseph.
>> Um, before we hop into that, we actually
have a couple news pieces that I did
want to show that are relevant to uh
this topic. The first one is there's
this guy on Twitter that's been tweeting
out some interesting stuff lately and
and it's like um yeah I think there are
some people commenting on it be like
yeah this is like well known you know
but you know it is what it is. Uh I I
thought that this was very interesting
material so I'll go ahead and share it
with you guys. Um the guy is NoiJR
um on Twitter and he shared that uh if
you create a uh XSS payload that looks
like this which I'm putting on the
screen but for audio listeners it is a
less than bracket with a question mark
and then less than bracket a and then an
href that had contains an SVG onload in
it then that will actually fire and the
reason for that is because um these you
know if you do not have an actual ual um
spec compliant
uh tag. So, you know, a less than sign
plus an A through Z uh character, then
it's going to encode those and not treat
anything else as a uh actual uh
attribute, which means they won't be URL
encoded, which means the things inside
of the href there will become the actual
HTML and everything else surrounding it
is just text uh that gets encoded. So,
um this these are kind of interesting uh
payloads. Yeah.
>> Uh there's another one as well which is
less than zero is not a valid tag. Yeah.
>> Um
>> they need to start with an asky letter.
Um
>> and and if they don't, they're not going
to be treated like a tag and the
encoding is not going to be applied to
the attributes or anything like that.
Mhm.
>> Um, a couple of the comments in here
were saying, "Hey, this is pretty much
only going to trick like syntax checkers
and like, you know, uh, syntax
highlighters and stuff like that." But I
think it might also be relevant in some
W bypasses as well that try to do
contextually aware
>> um, encoding or blocking. [snorts] It
makes me think about like what I'm sure
someone's on this before, but basically
all of the possible
um what's the opposite of compliant spec
breakant?
>> Yeah, spec non-compliant characters like
um that could occur in the first
character in the tags like that and I'm
sure that someone has fuss for that or
whatever. But
>> oh yeah, Shaz, I'm sure has has a list
for that or something like that.
>> Yeah.
>> Um so anyway, I just thought this was a
really interesting piece here. Uh,
I think this is the kind of stuff that
makes WFT bypasses um pretty pretty
doable. And we talked about this a lot
in the Ryan Barnett episode, but like
WFS are fighting a losing battle because
they just don't know what's going to be
happening if they're trying to do any
contextual aware um stuff. So,
>> I do think it's kind of an interesting
discussion on like
>> the novelty required for stuff to be
shared on social media because I think
that like
>> there's a lot of people who kind of hate
on anyone that shares like more beginner
information like this is known, but
that's clearly a spectrum, right? And
so, it's like where on that spectrum
should you like not post stuff or where
on the spectrum is like because it's
still useful for beginners still like
this is still like news to me. Maybe a
lot of people know it, but it was news
to me when I saw this tweet. I thought
it was neat, right? But um yeah, just
kind of interesting kind of meta topic
on you know what you should be sharing
because there definitely are some
um ex accounts and some other social
media accounts that share like such
basic information and then half of it's
wrong and they've kind of just feels
like more like snake oil or engagement
farming whereas I don't think this is
that at all.
>> No, this this is this guy sharing cool
cool stuff that he you know either
stumbled upon or learned and just wanted
to disseminate the information. And I
think you were the one that told me this
a while back, but like
>> it's something like only 20 or 30% of
your followers will see on average will
see like your actual post despite how
many views it gets. You know, there's
going to be a larger percentage that are
not going to be, you know, followers or
whatever.
>> Um, so if you really want to disseminate
information to your followers, you kind
of need to post it like two or three
times. Yeah. Uh, which is also
interesting because it's like, okay,
well, even if it even if somebody else
posted it, you know, they've got a
different audience base, you know, and
it does make sense to repost these
things and reshare these cool tips. And
I mean, to be honest, that's what we're
going to be doing all day on this
episode is like all the stuff that I'm
going to talk about here. Very little of
it is actually like just in research.
There's like maybe one or two areas.
>> It's super useful to have it rehashed
and it's super useful to have it
explained and it's super useful to have
it in one place.
>> Mhm. Formalized and and and organized.
Yeah, I agree. So, good stuff here by
Noki. Thanks for sharing that. Um, the
other one is, this is an interesting
one. I don't know if you saw this dude,
but there's this guy um, Bore Abel Hadi
who is creating uh, something called Rep
plus, which is a lightweight HTTP
repeater inside of Chrome DevTools. And
I just think this is a really
interesting place for this to live. uh
because uh you know a a lot of us are in
dev tools anyway, have our dev tools
open while we're hacking and yeah makes
sense that you might want to replay
requests in there especially if you are
like you know trying to do some
lightweight hacking or something like
that. So um really cool project I think
it is a little bit handicapped because I
think it is not uh HTTP1
compliant. I think it uses fetch and it
forces everything to be sent over HTTP2.
Um but very cool project nonetheless.
>> Yeah, I think in an ideal world if you
had to modify a request you would want
to modify it without going through a
proxy. A proxy is almost like an extra
step, right? And so I don't think we'll
ever get away from using proxy proxies
for a long time. But I think in like an
ideal world, you could just like hack
the request in the browser itself that
you're using.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Totally. That that is
interesting. Well, this is one of the
things that is also nice about Kaido's
like uh client server architecture is
like we could probably I frame Kaido
into DevTools. I actually I think I saw
somebody do that already.
>> That's funny and cool.
>> Um so if you really wanted to keep
everything in one spot, you could
actually put Kaido in DevTools. Um
interesting interesting thought.
>> Yeah.
>> Um all right, so that's all I had on the
news. You didn't have any any news items
this week that that cropped up, did you?
>> No, I did not. Have you played with Opus
4.5?
>> Dude, it's really good. Like, not only
do I think it's good, but I've seen
multiple people Well, okay, let's
actually clarify this because Gemini 3
is also incredible. Um, I guess one big
takeaway is they're both better than 5.1
in my opinion by like a pretty large
margin, but um I think Opus 45 has like
a very particular strength when it comes
to debugging and coding. I mean, Gemini
3 is obviously incredible at those as
well, but I think that Opus 4 5 is kind
of like a really new state-of-the-art
when it comes to front-end frameworks,
when it comes to debugging any kind of
issue. Um, like it, you know, I feel
like models sometimes would break down
when they were like trying to debug an
issue or they would like get a recurring
loop. Like I've seen a lot of people
comment on 45 breaking out of that
finally where it like doesn't get in
these like intense failure loops and it
can often like solve its own problems.
So,
>> yeah,
>> that's pretty sick, man. that that is a
big jump forward and I know that the
cloud models in particular are pretty
sick with uh um like tool calls and
stuff like that which is super important
as well. So
>> yeah I'm excited to see if you use it
much or if it comes in handy with your
project for your nomsec talk. So yeah,
the the Naham
Whoa. The Namcon uh talk that I'm doing
that I'll I'll also drop on the pod um
later this month. Uh we'll be doing
some, you know, AB testing with
different models and stuff like that.
But so far, man, it's clawed.
>> It is. you know, the the Gemini models,
as much as I love them and I use them
primarily, you know, outside of this
specific project, um, which is
essentially aification of our hacking
workflows, um,
it's it's not it's not doing as well
with tool calls. And
>> yeah, the tool calls just fail seem like
a larger percentage of the time, right?
>> Yeah, it's a little odd. Kind of a
bummer. I I'm I I am rooting for Gemini,
though. think I think Gemini if they can
fix that I think that they're going to
be the the best. But
>> yeah, I'm very bullish on Google in
general. I think they have the customers
that the distribution and their models
are incredible. Um I mean actually we
should talk about this for just a split
second. Nano Mano Banana Pro
>> is the wildest image editing piece of
software. It's basically
>> um Photoshop in a single tool call. Like
it's ridiculously good. I mean, it can
create advanced slides with lots of text
and advanced diagrams. Like, it would
not surprise me if it can create Yeah. I
mean, I've seen some that are like or
that are extremely good, but like um it
would not surprise me if it could
oneshot some like flow diagrams for like
hacking like oath flow diagrams. So, you
should you should test it for that. It's
really good.
>> Yeah.
>> But when you use it on 4K res, it's also
25 cents per image. So, be careful.
>> That gets expensive fast. Jeez. I mean,
yeah, you could just use the 1K
resolution and then it's like, you know,
4 cents or whatever, but
>> Wow. No, four cents. Yeah, that's that's
pretty doable. Um, all right, dude.
Let's get into let's get into the meat
of it. I've got a lot of fun topics I
want to go through today, and I'm
actually they're kind of not that
related, so I'll kind of let you take
your pick. Okay, we've got post
messages,
uh, third party cookies,
CSPTs,
iframe tricks, URL parsing, and client
side routes. Any of those stand out to
you as like the one we want to hear
about first?
>> Yeah, let's hear about thirdparty
cookies.
>> All right, third party cookies is
actually uh this is actually probably
the shortest section, so um this should
be pretty quick in the beginning. Um I
wanted to talk a little bit on this
episode about chips. Um which is uh
essentially how cookies are partitioned
uh when the partitioned value is uh or
attribute is attached to a cookie in
Chrome. Um because this is a something
that I think we're going to see gain
more adoption
>> than it currently has even and um uh it
is helpful for sort of uh threading the
needle in some of these cookie
situations that you're dealing with. Um
the the main thing that you need to
understand about this is that with chips
um cookies are no longer scoped just to
the to the um domain that they're on,
but they've also got a a key for them uh
that is tied to the top level page.
It that scheme plus ELTD plus one. So
whatever the TLDD is and then the the
domain
>> um and then inside of that right if
there's an iframe or something like that
it's tied to the host. So let's say
you've got um rhinorator.example.com
I frame framing in you know um
example.reszo.com
right? Uh so so
>> you use a different TLDD there.
>> I did I did but no that's they need to
be different. They need to be different.
So so let's do Okay. Let's let's keep it
simple. Let's do reinerator.example.com.
example.com and and as I framing
reszo.example2.com
okay the the the the key for that
>> is is going to be
>> um so first the tldd plus1 which is
exampample.com right cut off the
rhinerator piece so there's that and
then there's going to be the whole uh
second host which is reszo.example2.com
example2.com, right? That smooshed
together is going to be your your your
context for that specific cookie.
>> So, uh, if you have a different, you
know, key there, then it's not going to
be able to access that that cookie in a
different environment. Um, however, you
know, if there's, you know, gretme or
whatever.
And it iframes in reszo.example2.com,
>> because the TLD is the same example.com.
Yes. And, you know, reszo.ample2.com,
example2.com that key is going to
collide right and they will be able to
share cookies but otherwise you're not
going to be able to have access to
cookies inside of an iframe um if the
partitioned this is if the partitioned
value is set on that specific cookie um
so
>> so the way so right now most sites don't
have that you're saying
>> yeah that's right um but just just you
know that's a new cookie value or
attribute that has been attached so
something that I wanted to make people
aware of to be on the lookout for that
>> and is the primary mechanism for
implementing that the fact that they
want iframes to be more secure.
>> Yeah. Yeah. And it's also related to
some privacy pieces as well.
>> Okay.
>> Um so anyway, that was all I had on
that. That one doesn't have a ton of
like exploitation pieces. It's just
something important to understand is
that that how that key is generated et1
and then the actual ifrad host.
>> And will the parent one always be kind
of wild card like that or can the par
can can the parent one have a subdomain
as well? No, it's going to be it's going
to be ETLD plus one every time. Okay.
Scheme.
>> Um, all right. I'll pick the next one.
We'll go into post messages next. Okay.
Post messages are my [__] Do you know
what? All right. Tell me what you know
about post messages, Joseph. Do Do you
understand anything about post messages
or should I start from the beginning?
>> Very little. You should start from the
beginning. Yep.
>> Okay. I'll start I'll start from the
beginning. So, post messages. I want you
to I want you to in your explanation
explain it in such a way that there's an
analogy such that like I can create a
mental picture of it cuz I think the
biggest issue for most people's
comprehension of a new concept is that
they don't have a mental picture for it.
So I think S3 bucket is the best example
of this ever made like the name of the
thing is the analogy of the thing right
that's cool
>> and and and and so like because of that
everyone knows what a bucket is. this
place you put data, right? And so I
think like with post messages, it's it's
never like clicked strongly for me, even
though I understand that it's like this
site is sending a message to this site,
but it but it's not um the different
ways in which you can do that are not
overly clear because I don't have a good
mental picture. So if you have a good
analogy, do it.
>> And there's also some like overlap too
like I I remember trying to teach my
mentees about post messages and also
post
>> requests, you know, and those are not
the same thing even remotely, right? And
[clears throat] so, um, yeah, there is
some difficulty there. Post messages, I
mean, do kind of have that same imagery,
though, if you think about it as like a
little like a little post, like a
little, um,
the letter like, yeah, like a little
letter, right? Like the only thing I
could come up with is Japanese. But
yeah, the little letter um, and you're
kind of sending it from one tab to the
other. I
>> Is it always via JavaScript?
>> Yeah, it's always via JavaScript.
>> Okay, that helps me understand a lot.
Okay.
>> Yeah, it's always via JavaScript. It's
it's a feature of JavaScript um and the
browser, you know, uh kind of
collaborating together. And the concept
is you have multiple windows, right?
Those windows can be in an iframe or
they can be a tab. To be honest, it's
probably most most easy to think about
it being a tab.
>> Okay, maybe this is one big problem when
you say windows. Everybody knows what
you mean from a front end perspective.
>> Yeah.
>> If I'm not a front end guy, when like
what do you mean windows? Is it
literally tabs that are open?
>> Okay. So, good good differentiation. So,
a window can be a bunch of different
things. Okay. um you you've got a window
when you've got a tab open, right, in in
your browser. It can be a new window in
your browser, right? So you've got like
a new actual window, right?
>> Um uh it can be inside of an iframe.
>> Okay.
>> Um and those are those are the main ones
really.
>> Uh the there are other niche scenarios
like well okay technically it's not an
iframe it's like a picturein picture you
know there's various SDKs or whatever
that you can use to do different stuff
but um those are the main ones. Uh, and
what post message allows you to do is
just do communication between these
windows directly. Y
>> rather than via some API.
>> Cool. Yeah, that's how I always
understood it. Okay.
>> Yeah. So, um, you know, you use the SDK
that sort of comes with the browser,
right? So, it's, you know, window.post
message. You get a window reference, you
know, some way, and then you do
window.post message, and it just allows
you to send a JSON blob essentially. Or
>> so the other window always has a
listener.
>> Um, no. So the other window has to
register a listener. So that that's one
of the things that's interesting, right?
Is is like the other window is going to
get it, but the code isn't going to
react in any way if you don't register a
listener.
>> Right.
>> Yeah.
>> Um and so yeah, that's that's like a key
part of that. And then you know the the
listeners are kind of what we look at
often or and also messages being sent,
right? Because sometimes what'll happen
is you iframe a page and then it just
yeets sensitive data up to the parent,
right? No matter who it is, right?
>> Yeah. Yeah. because there's some code
that just says like parent.post or
something along those lines.
>> Exactly. Yeah. And it just yeets
information up. So that's sometimes how
that works. Um but other times uh you
know you also got to look closely at the
the listeners on the page, send it a
specific kind of message, then it'll
send other data out or do something on
the page, something like that.
>> So um anyway, post message not
necessarily like an advanced client side
topic. I would more consider this like a
intermediate or or lower client side
topic. Here are some of the things that
are more advanced uh about post messages
that not a lot of people know. Okay, so
um one, when you register a post message
listener, there is an event object
that's being passed into the uh the um
listener. So that event is what contains
the data. Okay, so if you do event.data,
that's the data that got sent in the
post message, right?
>> If you do event.source, source uh it
will it will uh give you a reference to
the window that sent that
>> that post message. If you do event
origin it will give you the origin of
the event that sent the uh origin of the
window that sent the post message. Okay,
>> perfect. Yep.
>> Um and what is interesting here is there
are such thing as null origins uh in
iframes. So, we're going to we're going
to sort of pop a little bit over to our
our iframe trick section as well. Yeah.
>> But, um, essentially, uh, a lot of times
what you'll see in a post message
listener is you'll see, okay, event.org
origin needs to, uh, you know, match
window.org, which means like this the
same uh, origin as sending the event or
sending the message is the same one as
me, right? So, I'm like I'm talking with
myself pretty much on a different page,
right? Mhm.
>> Um what's really cool though is if you
iframe a uh if you do a sandboxed
iframe, the origin for that uh iframe
becomes null.
>> Mhm. [clears throat]
>> And then here's the really really
interesting piece here. Okay. Um if you
do a
uh if you allow that sand or sandboxed
iframe to uh control popups to pop open
a new window. Yep. You can have it pop
open a new window to any site, right?
You know, any arbitrary site and it will
inherit the null origin of the page that
opened it.
>> Weird.
>> Okay. So, so now you've opened
google.com or whatever, right? Google
origin because if a post message
>> pulls the event.org origin of that page,
it will be null still.
>> Exactly. So, and and it's going to
compare it to its own window.org, right?
which will also be null because it
inherited the null origin. So now you've
just completely bypassed event.org
origin equals window.org origin.
>> That's a really cool. So if you ever see
that, there is a way to bypass it.
Basically
>> there is. Yeah. Um and it has some
constraints because now you're in a wind
a
um null origin iframe, you know, on this
page and a bunch of stuff might break.
Sometimes the JavaScript doesn't, you
know, run quite [clears throat] right
and stuff like that. Um but it is it is
possible to uh invoke that communication
uh and and bypass that check if it's
using um the objects window.org or just
origin.
>> Is that a security feature? Like is does
that get set to null automatically
because whenever you are trying to give
sandbox um iframe execution to something
it it gives you some sort of security
from the parent.
>> Yeah. So the the reason that exists is
and and I'm going to read it from the
from the docs here because I' I've
actually got it right here.
>> Um
>> so uh a sandbox resource is otherwise so
unless if you don't specify allow same
origin in the sandbox attributes then so
just what it is by default when you're
using sandboxed a sandbox resource is
otherwise treated as being from an
opaque origin which ensures that it will
always fail same origin policy checks.
>> Yeah. So they said it's a null. So that
it fails same origin policy.
>> Yeah. And and it's interesting because
it's not just null, right? Because if
you if you have two iframes that are
both null origin, they're going to say,
"Hey, we're both null origin. That fails
the same origin check." And I'm like,
"No, that's the same origin, but but no,
it's not. It's a different null." Right.
Um so those nulls aren't the same, but
they their string representations are
the same.
>> Are the same. Yeah.
>> Right. And so when you do window.org
origin and you get the string null back
and you compare that to the other null
origin. Yes.
>> That null then you're going to get a
hard match.
>> Yeah. So, so the practical tip here is
to basically look for places where that
is the security constraint. If it's
check if it's checking uh like if it's
saying event.org equals event.source,
then you know you've probably got a bug
because you can set them both to
>> null. Exactly.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Yeah. So, uh essentially I I
double checked it. I I was I was like
confused for a second because I was like
window.source. Wait, which one was it?
But it's it is, you know, event.org
essentially is what needs to be used to
get the null piece out of the the null
iframe sending a post message. And then
you compare that to window
>> window.org origin. Yep. So it's event
origin and window origin that if they're
doing that comparison check,
>> you're you're able to uh bypass it by
having them both set to null because it
does a string comparison of that value.
>> Exactly. Now, here's the interesting
thing. Typically, if the origin was null
on that page,
>> then you know there's not a lot of other
stuff you can do. You can't iframe hop
or anything like that. Um, but
you can do requests [laughter]
uh still fetch requests still work and
like so you can do a bunch of uh stuff
with it if you're able to like pop an
XSS inside of it or something like that.
Um, and this. So, um, yeah. So, I guess
that's where do I go down some other
post message stuff or do I go into the
iframe stuff now? [snorts]
>> Tricky, tricky, tricky.
>> Yeah, just whichever one's the most
relevant to what we were talking about.
>> Yeah, I I guess I'll stay in post
message and then we'll we'll go back to
it really quick. Okay. Um, a couple
couple other quick shout outs is that
post messages, a lot of people don't
know that post messages
>> the first parameter in, you know, post
message is your message and that can be
>> uh an object, not just a string. A lot
of people think it's a string and then
they run like JSON.parse on it or
whatever, right? That can be an actual
object. Okay?
>> So, you can just pass in curly brackets,
you know, whatever
>> um inside JavaScript and it will work
just fine. Um
uh what's also interesting there is that
you can send complex types through uh
post message some of them um for example
big int is a is a javascript object or
like type that is not like you know uh
JSON stringifiable
uh and you can send that through post
message.
>> Interesting. So, um,
>> so if there's ever something on the
other side that's expecting only JSON
stringifiable things, you're probably
going to go down a weird code path
that's not unexpected.
>> Yeah. And it it can also send some reax
related stuff. It can send like there's
a ton of stuff that that you can do with
that. Yeah. If if it is um not doing
like strict type checking.
>> Um, [clears throat] so keep in mind that
you're not just constrained to the basic
JSON types, right? String, array,
object, you know, integer, that sort of
thing. You can send more complex types
through co post message as well.
>> Cool. Yeah, that's awesome.
>> Okay, last one on last one on post
messages is this concept called message
ports. Okay, so you said you wanted a
little analogy. I'll give you an analogy
for this one. I tried with the other
one. You know, it's like a letter.
You're throwing it back and forth
between the different frames, right? Um,
but message ports are very much like one
of those little cans, you know, with a
string on the other end, right? and you
kind of put the can up to your ear and
you can listen and you can like throw
somebody else the other side of it and
then you know talk into it and then they
can listen. Um that's kind of like what
these message ports are. Okay. So
essentially instead of post messaging
into a window
>> you post message into a uh a message
port
>> and only the person that has a reference
to the message port on the other side
will be able to listen to that message.
Mhm.
>> Um [clears throat] so you you see this
sometimes nowadays um so that people
don't lose references to Windows and
like try to figure all that out. They
just shoot a port, the person that the
you know the other side has the port and
then we just communicate over this port.
Now um and depending on which tool
you're using to like monitor message
ports um you know or your post messages,
it may or may not hook these messages
ports. So understand that there could be
some some post message communication
happening in the background that you
know fancy tracker for Firefox or a
Fron's old post message tracker they may
not be hooking into.
>> Okay. Yeah. So these are not your
traditional style ports. This is like
another place where we're overloading
like the word message is overloaded and
the word port is overloaded here.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. So
>> it's a little different.
>> So these are not ports like on like a
web server and these are
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. These these are just these are
just like essentially it's an object.
You throw data into it, you know, and
and uh and the data comes out the other
side regardless of what frame has the
the reference. Um so it Yeah, I could
see your brain spinning a little bit.
>> Well, what I'm curious about is like
does does this um is this uh resilient
to like closing the other tab and
reopening? like is it stored like some
sort of like local storage where it's
like it knows that that page need can
like reopen the same port it had open
before the same message port like I'm
just curious like what value it adds.
>> I don't know I don't know how I don't I
don't know how you would store it. I I I
think I I think that it is not resilient
of that you know but
>> but it is still a browser feature. It's
not like a web page feature. Yeah, it
is. And it's facilitated via via the
browser and you know um you know you're
throwing these messages into instead of
a window you're throwing them into a
port.
>> Okay.
>> And then it's coming out the other side,
right? Is kind of the the thought behind
[snorts] it.
>> Yeah. Besides that, is it treated very
similar to post message? Like does it
still
>> have a doe event or like an event? Um
yeah. Okay. Okay. Cool.
>> It does. And um and I will also say if
you in the past I have been using some
weird tooling for these and like not
been able to catch message ports and I
think even fancy tracker for Chrome
which uh is really good. I think it it
sometimes it has some problems with
message ports recently I I've seen. So
um whenever I I suspect there's some
communication happening in the
background, I just find the event
listener and set a conditional
breakpoint inside of it uh that just
does console.log log and just logs to
the console. Okay.
>> Um as sort of like a redundant hook to
make sure I'm monitoring all
communication that comes through those
those um those message ports.
>> Yeah, that's a sick tip, right? I mean,
people like we're immediately going to
ask, okay, if it if if the things I'm
using to listen to post messages aren't
finding this, how do I do it, right? And
so, yeah, good tip.
>> Yeah. All right, so that's what I had
for post messages. Um let's go and jump
over to iframe tricks since we were
talking about that just a second ago. So
um the first thing that's really
interesting about iframes is you know
knowing how to create this no origin
which is essentially specifying the
sandbox attribute.
>> Um inside of that sandbox attribute you
can specify a bunch of different um like
permissions that uh the sandbox
attribute or the sandbox iframe has.
Okay. A couple of these are allow same
origin, allow scripts, you know allow
popups, those sort of things, right? Um,
and understanding what each one of those
does is really important to be able to
craft um, really good payloads um, using
these.
>> Okay, I have a really I have a really
kind of like dumb but maybe smart
question here.
>> I think when it comes to talking about
iframes, especially around front-end
hacking, it's it's like um, always a
little bit unclear in my mind like who
like if you're working in an iframe or
if you're the one creating the iframe to
then do the hacking, right? Because like
obviously a normal website can have an
iframe,
>> but then also like a normal website that
you're hacking can be ifframed by you on
your domain, which I assume is often
where you're hacking. But then I know
sometimes if you have like HTML
injection, then you're like on one of
their domains putting in your putting in
an iframe to one of their other domains
to pop a bug, right? And so I think that
some I think that sometimes is like a
little confusing to my brain to wrap
around it. So in this case, the majority
of the attacks come from you taking your
domain and you just putting in code that
creates and or instantiates an iframe to
the vulnerable domain, right? And that's
almost what you're always doing. Or or
are you then also using that to then do
post messages to it to the uh to the
other window?
>> It's it's all of the above. You just
described the the beauty of iframes and
like freaking client side loveliness,
dude. Um is that Yeah. All of those,
right? There could there could be an
iframe on their page. There could be an
iframe on your page. You could be
ifframing your own page. I framing your
own page to create a null origin which
is a separate origin from your attacker
page and then use that null origin to
open up another page. You know, like
there there's just like a ton of fun.
Okay.
>> That could be had. Aren't you just
Aren't you just thrilled? You're not
looking as thrilled.
>> No, no, no, no, no. I'm just thinking
I'm just thinking through like if
there's like an easy way to
conceptualize this. Is it kind of like
um
is it kind of like post messages
basically have and not just post
messages but I guess other iframe tricks
as well. But is it basically like you
have a a a set of tools in your toolbox
which are both the ways in which um like
the different parameters with which a
message can be sent which are like kind
of the things that you mentioned above
right like whether it is a null origin
or not
>> or and like the domain that you're on
and then also depending on the cookies
that exist for that domain and then
those um those sets of attributes
control both what you can do and what
might be vulnerbable. herbal and so you
have to like basically test all of those
different things.
>> This is good. This is elevating my
thinking a little bit here from my nuts
and bolts. Okay, so let me try to
abstract it a little bit for you. Um
>> uh having you know an iframe is for
several purposes. One is a window
reference, right? So I need to be able
to reference a a victim's you know
window of that origin, right? So that's
useful for scenarios where you're like
sending post messages or or something
like that, right? Um so getting a window
reference, an iframe is one way to do
that. Another way to do that is
window.open which just opens up a new
tab
>> by get but by getting a window reference
you mean like the victim would go to
your website. Then you would you would
load an iframe to the website that has a
vulnerability on it and and then you can
reference that window now and you can
now attack the victim because before
that you didn't have a window to even
reference.
>> You need a place to stand, right? you
know like you know what's that that
quote from like some philosopher like
give me a lever and a place to stand and
I can move the earth
>> our committee's lever yeah
>> yeah that that's it and and and so you
know that's kind of how I think about
this a lot of time is I need a place to
stand when I'm when I am you know using
these window references
>> um so that's one one way the other the
other piece is oftentimes or sometimes
you can incur constraints on those
domains uh when they are in an iframe or
Um yeah, you can control the context in
which they load. That maybe that's a
little bit better, right? Um and you see
this with credentialist iframes, you see
this with um sandboxed iframes, right?
Um these are ways that you can
>> control the context in which
Okay, this is making sense to me now
because you control the parameters of
the iframe being loaded. If you load it
with different settings, if you want to
think about it that way, then that
actually can change what occurs inside
of that iframe.
>> Exactly. Yeah. So, so a really good
example of this is um one that I
mentioned just a second ago. Let's say
you you create a attacker controlled
page and that attacker controlled page
has a null origin attacker controlled
iframe,
>> right? So, I'm framing myself. Y
>> I've got it set to null origin and then
I from there I I have in the sandbox I
have allow pop-ups and allow scripts,
right? So, I can run JavaScript and I
can uh allow pop-ups for this sandboxed
iframe.
>> Yeah. So from that sandbox iframe I do a
window.open to you know the victim's
site or whatever. Now that victim site
has the null origin as well right.
>> Um it it inherits this is one thing that
I really want to emphasize here. It
inherits the sandboxed properties
>> of [clears throat] the attacker control
null origin page. Yep.
>> Okay. So if you if you said um let's say
you said no no no script, right? Let's
say you said no script and you did the
popup via a uh an a a a tag or something
like that, right? Any straight HTML,
right? That victim page is now running
without any JavaScript.
>> That's so weird. So that's so so if they
ended up on rounder.com and you did
this, all of a sudden a new window would
pop up to the to the victim website
google.com
>> to google.com with no JavaScript
actually
>> with no JavaScript. JavaScript is not
allowed to run.
>> Okay.
>> You know, and it and and that's one of
the beautiful things about this is like
you are incurring constraints.
>> Yeah. unanticipated constraints on these
third party sites. Yes. Right.
>> Um and another example, and I I'll give
a shout out to um
>> uh to Jorian in the the uh cool research
channel on the critical thinking Discord
is just constantly dropping cool [__] in
there, man. [clears throat] Um hopefully
by the time this episode goes live,
he'll have his write up um on
lab.ctv.show up on this sort of thing.
But um one of the things he dropped in
the chat recently was that he was able
to use this and he the things he
specified were allow same origin, allow
pop-ups, allow scripts, but he did not
specify allow forms. So what was
happening is there was a page that was
autosubmitting a form.
>> Right? And he needed it to not
autosubmit a form so that he could he
could attack it, right?
>> Uh and so he used this constraint. It
inherited the sandbox properties of the
other origin. Yep.
>> Right. of of the other and and it
doesn't necessarily have to be a null
origin, right? In this scenario, he he
said allow same origin. So, it was just
>> the normal origin for this page. Yeah.
But it did inherit the fact that it's
not allowed to submit forms. So, when it
went to autosubmit the form,
>> it failed, right? And so there there are
lots of ways that you can sort of
manipulate these target pages that have
been spawned from sandboxed iframes.
Does that make sense?
>> Yep. Yeah. And and you know, a lot of
these again are affecting different code
paths. like they may have expected that
to always autosubmit and so when it
didn't what happens
>> some sort of fallback right you know
like and man sometimes you see the
craziest fallbacks like uh I think I've
seen one of the fallbacks I've seen for
like not being able to parse JSON was
just run eval on the string and it's
like what [laughter]
>> um
>> fallback execute RC
>> yeah exactly it's like okay uh yeah so a
lot of these fallbacks can trigger
unanticipated code path paths. Um so
knowing about these uh sandboxed uh like
attributes that you can apply to these
third party sites can be really
valuable.
>> Yeah.
>> Um I will say there is an exception to
that. So I I said I I talked about
sandbox inheritance here. Um the
exception to that is allow top
navigation. So there is this specific um
flag that you typically need to specify
in your sandboxed uh iframe.
>> Yep. that's that will allow it to
navigate the top level page. There's a
specific exception made in the docs
for inherited window, you know, windows
that have inherited those sandboxed
properties from a iframe. Uh, but it was
opened via window.open, so it's in its
new tab, right? Because it's saying,
okay, well, hold on a sec. Like, we
can't not let them navigate themselves,
>> right?
>> Right. And it because it's in a new
window. So that is gonna have implicitly
have allow top navigation associated
with it. Um and it will be able to
navigate itself.
>> What does allow topnav do?
>> Allow top navigation allows you to
navigate the URL bar for that tab.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah.
>> So I just wanted to make sure I put that
that um caveat out there.
>> Are you tracking with me so far? I know
that that's very convoluted.
>> I'm tracking extremely well with you and
that's that's great because I you know
came in not knowing you know nearly as
much. So, I think even our beginner
listeners will have followed almost all
this. So,
>> that's great. I I I think um I think a
lot of times like I mean I love this
stuff obviously, but I you know whenever
I go to talk about it, it's so nuanced
and convoluted. I'm sure I'm sure
freaking demo or like some some turbo or
whatever Jorian some some of the
listeners are going to be like find
something that I said in this episode
and put it in the corrections channel.
So, please do because that's how I learn
as well. But um this is uh is my best my
best shot at representing these
concepts.
>> You're doing great.
>> All right. So uh let's talk about two
more things. Uh credentialist is one of
them which is another attribute on
iframes and this one was it's fairly new
actually. Uh but the thing you need to
know about this, we've covered it on the
pod before is that if you apply the
credential list attribute to an iframe,
it just means that it is using a new
ephemeral context. So no cookies, no
local storage, no no nothing associated
with that domain. It is going to survive
that credentialist context.
>> Um and and so that's useful if you've
got, you know, a cookie that you need
not to be set for your attack to happen.
But of course that cookie is going to be
set if the if the user even uses this
website, right?
>> So you need to like get them in a state
where
>> they don't have the cookie set, but
they're still logged into the page or
something like that, right? Um
credential list uh is really good for
this. Um and here's something that I
should have looked up before the pod.
Actually, maybe we'll pause and I'll
look it up right now. I'm not sure that
credential list inherits on window.open.
So let me go check that right now. Okay,
it doesn't look like it inherits the
credential list uh attribute. So, this
one's only uh helpful if you're like
inside of an iframe itself, which does
make this a little tricky because not
every page nowadays is is ifraable due
to like xframe options and CSP. So,
>> yeah.
>> So, that's an interesting little nuance,
but it has saved our butts a couple
times. [laughter]
>> Um, you got that one. I know we've
covered that one before.
>> Yeah. No, that's great. I was going to
ask, are there any other iframe
attributes that you think are key that
we haven't mentioned yet or that you
think are interesting or we've mentioned
most of them?
>> Um, yeah. I mean, these are the ones
that just kind of popped into head. Um,
there there are a couple things. The
name attribute is really important,
right? That that controls the name of
the frame.
>> Um, and we'll talk about that one in
just a sec with window hijacking. Um
there are lots of interesting other
attributes like you can specify a CSP
that uh the victim page must conform to
and if it doesn't load that CSP then
it's not going to load you know. So
there's there there are some interesting
things you can do with that. Um but
we'll we'll we'll save those for a time
when I've uh researched them a little
bit more recently and can talk about
them more uh more clearly. Um the one I
did want to specify though was window
hijacking which goes back to the name
attribute that I was mentioning before.
So
Um
here's a really cool thing. Um you can
name your windows and your frames and
stuff like that various things. So uh
let's say you name your wind uh your
window uh ABC or whatever right I if uh
there there is a scenario where you can
force a victim page to open
their window.open into that iframe. So
so consider this scenario. Okay. And
actually, if you want to visualize it,
Joseph, so you can see, click that um
frame hijacking attacker page uh link
that I put in the in the um doc there. Y
>> um consider this scenario.
>> You've got an attacker controlled page.
>> Um you embed inside of that p uh page an
iframe to the victim site called ABC.
>> Sure.
>> Okay. So that's the name.
>> Then you do a window.open to a victim
page. that victim page uh you know goes
through some oath flow or whatever and
then does a window.open open with the
name ABC, right? Of course, it wouldn't
be ABC. It' be like, oh, login session
or whatever, right?
>> What will happen is it will look for any
other pages in the browsing context.
Yes.
>> That are the same origin as itself. So,
it has to be the same as victim.com.
>> Sure.
>> And then it will open into that iframe
>> rather than doing a window popup,
>> right? And since you embedded that
iframe in the first place, right, you
control where it's pointing to. So then
you can, you know, redirect it to
something else and then or like put
something in the hash or something like
that and then when it redirects back to
the victim page and that thing is still
in the hash, it might try to read the
hash and do something with it, right?
Um, so this is what I'm talking about
like having iframes open allow you to
control the context in which pages are
running. And in this scenario, we just
hijacked a a popup, right? And instead
we put it in our attacker controlled
page where we have control over it.
That's super weird and cool that that
works.
>> Isn't that amazing?
>> Yeah. I do think that another disjoint
in my understanding is from like what is
possible inside of an iframe
>> that is iframe from like attacker.com,
right?
>> Sure.
>> Like that's interesting.
>> You can redirect it for sure. Like that
is
>> you said you can you can't just like
reach in and then get those cookies.
Right. Right. Because there's Yeah.
There's still you can't even see them on
the way in even though you framed it.
>> Right.
>> Right. Right.
>> Yeah. Yeah. So it's interesting. It is a
little weird.
>> Like knowing the nuances about what's
possible with that iframe is another
reason why I think there's like a gap in
understanding between people who are
like really in the front end versus
those that aren't.
>> Yeah. Yeah. And and the only way to get
that is experimentation is for you to
listen to this podcast and like pop open
your browser and like build pages that
represent the scenarios we're talking
about and toy around with it yourself.
Yeah.
>> Um or you can do what you do, which is
understand it at like just a deep enough
level where you can say, "Hey, this is
weird. Hey Justin, this is your [__] and
this is what I do for you with AI stuff,
you know, and uh and then we kind of
bounce off of each other, which is
great.
>> No, I think this is huge, though. And
and honestly, I think all of this front
end stuff is extremely
uh important and good even for kind of
this like new AI hacking stuff because
there's so much HTML injection and so
much like room for XSS and other
front-end like um sessory when it comes
to all of these different AI apps that
are popping up because they very often
are either I frame it in or doing
translation between markdown to HTML or
they just straight up have XSS to begin
with. So no, I think this is like all
extremely um beneficial. So,
>> so, so here's another really interesting
thing. Okay. Often times what'll happen
is let's say you're on like some AI
page, right? And it's generating a
markdown output which has a link in it.
>> Yep.
>> Um, if that link is allowed, if that a a
tag is allowed to have the target
attribute,
>> then you've got something really cool
here. Okay. Uh, because what you can do
is let's say let's say we're on Gemini
for example. Okay. Gemini uh has an
invisible iframe, you know, in it to do
like analytics or like, you know, supply
whatever feedback form or something like
that, right?
>> That that feedback form or whatever is
named, you know, ABC.
>> If you can get the AI to spit out a a
tag that has target equal to ABC, when
they click that link, it's going to open
into that iframe.
>> Wow.
>> So now you've got like a persistent
invisible iframe with your attacker
controlled page inside of Gemini, right?
And unless that iframe is sandboxed, you
can also do like you you can uh do like
top.loation
navigate and and change the top level
page, right? And and there's just or you
can send post messages from like an
advantaged position and bypass coupe
like
>> I'm going to go I'm going to go find you
this a place where we can control target
in libraries. I'm gonna go.
>> Absolutely. Please, please let me know
because like um the target unfortunately
the target attribute is a little bit
tricky to smuggle in there, but if you
can, there's like a ton of really cool
stuff you can do with it.
>> So, keep that in mind.
>> Um dude, we man I your boy can yap about
client side stuff. Okay. Um let me see
where we want to go next. Let's talk
about URL parsing. Okay. Um,
this one is kind of an
>> I want to make sure we hit CSPT before
we uh sign off to
>> we can't skip that one.
>> We'll hit CSPT as well. Um, let's jump
to URL parsing first.
>> Sure.
>> Uh, start us off with a basic one.
Oftent times back slash gets converted
into uh double back or double slash.
>> Yep.
>> Which uh will allow you to actually
produce an absolute URL rather than a
relative URL that causes so many bugs.
So, uh, like keep that in mind.
>> Yeah.
>> That's also probably applicable to AI
because like
>> the like I just had the best bug of a
Amazon IPC and it was a bypass where the
um markdown image rendering happened
with slash.
>> So, if they then go fix that with slash,
then back slash slash would potentially
work to bypass it. Right.
>> Exactly. Yeah. and and you can do, you
know, if it's inside of an attribute or
whatever, you can do all sorts of, you
know, encodings, HTML encodings, that
sort of thing. So, there's lots of lots
of depth that that can happen there. Um,
this is one that is is also quite
interesting is that recently and I think
we covered this on the pod as sort of
like a side note when it first came out,
but recently
uh Chrome conformed to Safari's behavior
about parsing JavaScript URIs such that
JavaScript URIs can now have a host name
associated with them. So, so if you do
javascripterator.com
slash rhinerator.com is the host name
for that JavaScript URI which doesn't
make a lick of sense.
>> That's really weird
>> cuz like that's not what the URI is for.
>> Yeah.
>> Right. And they had it the safer way
before which is with that it was null
>> but then they were like ah well you know
the spec says that it should be like
this and Safari is doing it this way so
we're also going to do it this way. And
the hackers were like, "Yes." You know,
like [laughter]
um so
>> have you seen this used already?
>> Oh, yeah. Yeah. Yeah. I've used it many
times and I've seen many people use it.
Um but this now makes it so that if
there is a new URL, right, you know,
parsing of of this this um scheme
>> and it does host name and compares it to
like the host name of this page or
something like that, then you can have
that. But then when they do location uh
you know window.loation application
equals this, it will run JavaScript. And
you can just do like percent at the end
of the JavaScript to create a new line
because SL slash is a comment in
JavaScript, right?
>> So, do you see how that works? Right?
Like JavaScript slash now we're in a
comment.
>> There's a comment. Yep. Then you get the
next line.
>> Who cares what happens there, right?
It's like just the stars aligning in so
many good ways. Isn't that awesome?
>> That's cool.
>> Yeah. Um, so that one's a really good
one to
>> Very selen features unlock a bunch of
bugs.
>> Yeah. Yeah. which I mean I guess people
probably reported it as like Firefox
only bugs already, right? But
>> yeah, and I've reported it as a Safari
only bug, but last time I reported it uh
you know before they they changed it. I
saw in the, you know, in the critical
thinkers channel, we've got like the
data feeds or whatever and I saw uh on
the intent to ship feed that uh they
were going to change it and I put that
in my report and they paid me the full
thing like it wasn't going to because
they're like Croc Chrome is going to
ship this so it's you know we're just
getting ahead of the curve and I was
like yes
>> that's awesome.
>> Um so that one's a cool one. The other
one that's really interesting and sort
of relates back to post messages as well
is that you know the the the string null
that represents the null origin uh is
kind of weird because it is just a
string [laughter] and uh the that string
like can be perceived in different ways.
So here's an example of how this might
work. one of the before they I think the
prevalence of uh the URL parsing um
framework that they have in in in
JavaScript now uh one of the ways that
you would commonly see to parse a uh a
URL is to create document create a an a
tag and then set the href to a specific
URL right um and so let's say you got a
post message and you wanted to extract
the host name from that post message in
a in a reliable
logic that I've seen before is say
document.createelement a a.href equals
event.or origin. Right? So you're
setting the the href of that a tag to
the origin of the uh post message.
>> Uh and then grab the host name of the a
tag which is pre-populated into that
like object.
>> Yeah. Um, what's interesting is that if
you send this from a null origin, it
passes null into the href of the A tag.
And null, if you just put null as a
string, it says, "Oh, that's a that's a
relative URL. That's slashnull, [snorts]
right?" And so what is the host name of
a relative URL? Oh, that's the current
page that we're on, right? And so it
just fills in the very helpfully fills
in the current the current pages hosted
>> again by the stars aligning only.
>> Exactly. Right. And and and then it
compares it to itself and it's like
always passes. Right.
>> That's cool.
>> Um so I've seen that logic a couple
times when they use um create element A
as like their their way to extract the
host name. This does not work in new URL
unfortunately like uh uh because of some
constraints that they have uh in the
system for that. Uh but it does work in
other methods of extracting the host
name.
>> Yeah.
>> Um okay, you said you wanted to go to
CSPTs next.
>> Yeah.
>> Um dude, like the thing is I've talked
about CSPTs so much on this podcast, so
>> I don't know. I could go a little bit
deeper than what I've got in the in the
dock there, but um yeah, I guess I'll go
a little bit deeper. Okay. So, um
>> this is advanced techniques. All right.
>> All right. See, CSPTs, I'm not going to
explain what CSPs are. Yeah. You know,
TLDDR, you get data from the URL or from
the path, you stick it into a sub
resource request, and you can induce
path reversal. There's also another
subset of these. I will say that I don't
really know what to call them. I kind of
think maybe it's like request hijacking,
but this is when you take something from
a query parameter or a path and you
inject it directly into the domain of a
fetch request, right? So, it's not a
path reversal. You're just overwriting
what host
>> the the fetch request, the subresource
request is is actually going to, right?
So, be on the lookout for this.
>> And this is common in like cloud
providers and stuff, right?
>> Yeah, totally. You you you know what I'm
talking about actually. Um yeah, but
these sort of um these sort of
vulnerabilities are are pretty common.
And uh I would say one thing that that
is really uh useful to exploit these is
knowing that you can exploit the
difference between what what the browser
perceives and what actually hits the
fetch sync. Uh and this was a great
shout out by Turbo. I think he mentioned
it on his episode or maybe it was in the
the the chat, but anything like
percent09 or like new lines and stuff
like that, all of that just gets
straight stripped from anything past
passed into fetch
>> as a part of the host name. So you can
do, you know, rhinorator tab.com
>> and and it will just pull the tab out
when it does the fetch. Um, so if
there's any sort of like parsing or like
um analysis of that data that you're
passing in, you can really often times
finagle it by, you know, adding white
space throughout there.
>> Um,
>> and then and then also just be on the
lookout for different levels of encoding
here. Like I think that's where a lot of
the vulnerabilities occur. You're not
always just going to be able to insert
like a slash or, you know, a backslash
or something. You got to try percent 2F,
percent 5C, percent 25F, percent 25C,
[clears throat]
percent 4, right, for the ad sign, you
know, like all sorts of things like this
that can sort of break these various
contexts.
>> Yep.
>> Um, okay. Um,
going from there, let's talk a little
bit about client side routes. Um, client
side routes, I don't know, man. Like I
feel like I don't really know how to
hack applications that don't have client
side routes anymore, man. Like it's just
so overpowered
>> that in single page applications that
you just have access to
>> essentially like the full app in the JS
files like right in front of you.
>> Yeah, I've been doing um hacking on
Hacker One challenges that don't have
that and they're it's so frustrating. I
mean, it's also really rewarding when
you find a new path, especially if it's
one that like you're not supposed to
have access to and the page actually
loads. It's like a massive adrenaline
rush, but it is weird to go back to
those because so many pages are just
single page apps these days.
>> Yeah, I think we talked about it on the
pod like last week or the week before,
but like you know there's just a totally
different approach you've got to take
where you're just like, you know,
looking for patterns, brute forcing
stuff. it is a lot more brute force
heavy whereas with spas um
>> all you have to do is just figure out
how these routes are defined and and I I
think the best way to do this in so many
levels is just reverse engineer what
you've got right what page am I on okay
well that page has got a route somewhere
so just take the page put it into you
know control shift F in dev tools where
you're searching all of the JS files and
then find where the the place where the
routes are defined and then just look at
every single route right that's like one
of the first things to do on my
checklist
uh is just like you know go through
every single route, understand
everything that's happening and go from
there.
>> Um
>> yeah. Yeah.
>> Yeah. I like that second tip that you
have here that's basically you do it
seems like you almost do the same thing
for parameters like what what what and
how are all these parameters used? How
are they parsed? What do they do?
>> Yeah, totally. And and and you know look
for the nuances in the route definitions
as well. uh you know because sometimes
there'll be like param like uh colon you
know path ID or or you know object ID or
whatever in there. So they're taking
path parameters right um uh and then
also like you said look at the way
they're the framework they're using
they're probably going to do consistent
parsing or access to given uh query
parameters. So are they using URL search
params? are they using like you know a
react or a view um uh piece here to grab
grab query parameters and that sort of
thing and then look at every single
query parameter that ever gets parsed
ever in the whole app right and and
understand every single piece of data
that you can pass into this application
by a by a force by by forcing them into
a specific URL
>> okay so I've obviously heard you talk a
lot about client side pass reversals and
I've seen them a lot of places but it's
just dawning on me that
>> I think that I've fa failed to test for
a ton of places cuz I definitely see
like the slash colon ID or whatever. But
if that's ever controlled by me, I can
always check for if I name that object
or if it's like attacker controlled. If
I have like for example let's just say
it's a username like if it's like slash
>> slash user slashreso if I go make my
username dot dot slash what happens
right like
>> yeah there there's scenarios where you
can get stored cpt with that right where
it will load you know from the database
your name and then that gets causes a
path traversal like what is going on
>> um
>> yeah and then yeah you can also just do
you know it's a little bit trickier when
it's path parameters because you got to
do like various levels of encoding and
stuff like that. But let's say you've
got slash user slash, you know, user ID.
>> Yep.
>> You know, do slash user percent 2f, you
know, dot dot percent2f, you know,
>> and you know, have that encoded version
and if that if it's resolving those,
then do percent 252f, right? So you can
still find path traversals inside of
path parameters. Um,
>> so definitely be on the lookout for
that. Uh the other thing is that one of
the ways that you know with with the
onset of same site cookies which you
know I think is I feel like that's a
little bit more of an inter intermediate
topic but um uh with the with the onset
of same site cookies um curfs are
getting a little bit more challenging
and one of the ways that you can exploit
curfs um pretty reliably nowadays is
just by making sure that the request
originates from the attack the victim's
page um and a lot of times that happens
via these callback act routes where it
hits a third party provider
whatever I want to link my account and
then it comes back to this page on a
specific route that is responsible for
completing that linkage right but if you
can just grab your attacker control data
redirect the victim to that finalize
route right then it will send a you know
a post request or whatever to modify the
victim's account then boom you got a
sort of a curf
>> oh that's cool that's really cool
>> yeah um and then sometimes you can
hijack those as well, right? Maybe
there's a CSPT inside of that and it's
sending a post request. So, you use it
to hit a different endpoint and then do
a different curve, right? Um, so it's
this whole CSPT to curf idea that was
really covered well by um, DOESC in
their in their CSP uh, paper they did a
while back. Um, so lots of lots of neat
nuances there. Um, dude,
>> your throat going out?
>> My throat is getting getting a little
raspy. I'm going to close it up with um
just one two more little quick shouts
and that is one I kind of mentioned URL
search params earlier but that is a uh a
class in JavaScript that is used to
parse
>> like query parameters right so really
good place for DOM DOM logger++ um hooks
and also uh just control Fing for URL
search params to see where parameters
are being parsed.
>> Yeah. Um, so that's just a little tip
I'll throw out there. And also do not
ignore on hash change events because
hash change is something that you can
control as a as a hacker, right? On your
evil page. I don't know if this is
something that's commonly
>> I didn't know that. Yeah. So, how does
this happen?
>> Yeah. So, let's say you do a window.open
to a victim page, right? And you know
what URL they're on.
>> You can do that same window.open again
to that same URL with a different hash
and it will swap the hash without
refreshing page.
>> Oh, interesting. and it will trigger the
onash change event on that page and
sometimes when the hash changes various
things will occur on that page. Um so
>> that's really cool.
>> Is is on hash change how like um it like
jumps to
um different like table of contents
buttons or no?
>> Uh sometimes depending on Yeah.
>> Or is that on page load? Uh there is
some functionality for that but I I I
think like most of the stuff now that
I'm talking about here is just hooked
into this event that you can register
that says hey whenever the hash changes
I want this code to run and you look at
that code and you say oh okay well one
of those is a redirect so I redirect to
this hash and then it you know
>> drops your JavaScript source or
something like that you know your
JavaScript URI into a window location or
something.
>> Yeah.
>> Um so
great stuff there. Um, the last thing
that I had here, this is, and this is
just like a random piece that I decided
to throw into this episode. I probably
should have bumped this up to the top,
uh, when covered it during news, but
it's actually a post from Terjank back
from 2021. Wow.
>> That somehow recently came across my my,
uh, X feed. Um, and he was saying that
something that really blew my mind,
which is, and this is something I guess
to cover a little bit more from an
higher level perspective is like there's
this concept of the DOM, right? Which is
the rendered um uh the document object
model that it's like your HTML that's
being shown on the page.
>> And a lot of times for stuff to run, you
have to create an element in JS and then
attach it into the page, right? You
could do document.body.appen child or
something like that. So you you create
the element now it's just living in
JavaScript land and then you insert it
into the DOM.
>> Makes sense.
>> What's really weird here is that uh what
Tjank tweeted out was that like you can
create an an element. So let's say you
do document.createelement div or
whatever and then you say div.inhtml
equals you know image source equals x on
error equals alert one. Right?
[clears throat]
>> That still has not been inserted into
the DOM yet. So it's not like it
shouldn't be rendering. Uh but for some
reason that will run uh that on on error
handler will run. Uh
>> are there any protections like obviously
DOM purify uh implies that it's
purifying the DOM?
>> Yeah. Yeah. Would that like not get
purified because it's not?
>> That's kind of the first thing that came
to my mind as well was like I feel like
some of these parsers are probably like
depending on the fact that they can like
take the HTML and stick it inside of
like another HTML element that they
crafted in the JavaScript, you know, VM
or whatever
>> and then like do stuff to it,
>> right? But but if you even get it to
that point, you're already done because
it's going to run.
>> Yeah, that's that's what makes me think.
It makes me think that there are a lot
of cases where people have like tried to
get XSS but failed but they never tried
a HTML.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Well, it's very it's very
interesting and there could be other
nuances around enter HTML because I know
that that's you know that is a a pretty
dangerous function that a lot of um uh
people will try to uh avoid when they're
doing these parsing. But I I still
wouldn't have thought it would have
triggered I I wouldn't have thought that
it would trigger even without being
inserted into the DOM. And it and it is
interesting as well because I know this
is just making me think a little bit. I
know that there is a bug in DOM purify
where if you put a meta tag in into the
DOM purify like uh parser that metatag
will be applied to the page uh even
though it got sanitized away. So, so
they are like definitely taking that and
doing something with it where
>> Yeah.
>> So, I don't I don't think this is a dumb
purify bypass because that's is like a
very vanilla paper that that I'm seeing
here. But like but like um there's
definitely some weird nuance of uh of
that because that's the same thing
that's happening with this meta tag that
uh JRock mentioned back on his episode
back in the day. So,
>> something odd something odd's happening
there. I got to double click into that a
little bit.
>> I'm sure something is will come out of
this episode. Almost definitely. Yeah,
for sure, man. Um, all right, that was a
lot of Justin yapping. You got any
questions about any of that or do we
think we're uh we're good for now?
>> No, dude. I think you explained it super
well. I u It's funny. This is like the
advanced episode, but we also were like
super beginner all the way to the
advanced stuff. So, I think this will be
super useful for both sets of listeners,
which is probably great because if it
was only advanced, then I feel like half
people stop listening immediately. But
there will be enough listeners like me
that will like hang on for the ride
because you uh you bridged it so well.
So, thank you for that.
>> Of course, man. Yeah, I think there's a
lot of a lot of both here. A lot of, you
know, covering some of the foundational
concepts, but also like this super weird
like double null origin iframe stuff
that's that's pretty whack. So,
hopefully we triggered some some
advanced minds out there to go down some
some paths with some of this stuff and
help some of the beginners along as
well.
>> Yeah, dude. Sweet.
>> All right, man. Peace. Good episode.
>> And that's a wrap on this episode of
Critical Thinking. Thanks so much for
watching to the end, y'all. If you want
more critical thinking content, uh,
[music] or if you want to support the
show, head over to ctbb.show/isord.
You can hop in the community. There's
lots of great highlevel hacking
discussion happening there on top of
[music] master classes, hackalongs,
exclusive content, and a full-time
hunters guild. If you're a full-time
hunter, [music] it's a great time. Trust
me. All right, I'll see you there.